hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this task automation course
this is the part two
from the test case design section so if
you have not watched the part one
so go ahead and watch the previous
session where we have discussed about
what is test case design sheet
what are different attributes how you
can create them in tosca right so once
you do that you can come here and then
we can learn about different instances
right so once you create your attributes
you need to create different instances
of those attributes right so these
instances are nothing but they are
different variations of your attribute
in your application right
so for example when we created an
attribute called customer type or user
type right so it had got different
values in your application it could be a
registered user a unregistered user
or it could be a business user or a
technical user right so there are four
different variations of a single
attribute which is the user
okay now all these different four values
or variations are known as instances so
you have to create four different
instances of that attribute in your test
sheet
okay
now uh coming to uh different properties
of these instances right so when you
create an instance it has got
certain properties which can be um
altered based on your
scenario of your test case okay
so the different properties are
basically two important properties which
you should consider are character and
position okay now character
this character property it tells us
whether it's a valid instance an invalid
instance or a straight through instance
okay so we can toggle between these
three different types of character
properties okay
now if it's a valid uh type of character
instance right
then uh that should be no error expected
when you run this
in your application okay so
it's the default type of uh character
property value which is assigned to
every instance if you don't change it
and
when you put um a
instance as a valid character instance
then basically it should not fail
okay or there should be no error when
executing this particular test case in
this particular instance okay
the next type is invalid
although this doesn't mean that um
it's an instance which should always
fail no
uh
it's
it's an instance where it will give you
an error and it's a valid error because
you have given an invalid input right so
that type of instance is known as the
invalid character instance
and then there is the third type which
is the straight through
value for character instance now this is
um the scenarios where um
it's the most critical part of your
application and the business flow is the
is most frequently used by the customers
right so you should define your
instances
as straight through
which you consider it as a happy path
right which has the fewest dependencies
in your application and also it is easy
to implement right so all these
instances should be considered or should
be defined as straight through right so
you always expect these instances to at
least pass whenever you are running all
your test cases
okay so when there is less time and you
have to
execute a lot of test cases what you can
do is you can just execute the straight
through cases because these are the high
risk instances and they are very easy to
run or they are your happy path okay so
if they run successfully you can make
sure that uh at least your high risk
functionality of your application is
working okay
now coming to position which is another
property for an instance
and this tells you whether um
a instance is a boundary value instance
or a inner value instance okay so there
are two types
and
if you have uh learned the testing
concepts right so this is the pretty
basic uh concept which is used for
designing your test cases okay so
whenever you're trying to define um what
kind of test cases you are going to
design from the requirements so you
consider the boundary values and um the
equivalence class partitioning okay so
these are two very common
uh keywords which you heard in testing
okay
now boundary values what are these uh so
when you have a range of values
the
boundaries are considered um as the
extreme values okay so
uh you cannot have uh valid inputs
beyond these boundaries okay so for
example if we have the product quantity
um and it
accepts a value between a range 1 to 10
so
your valid values are should be between
1 to 10 right
and 1 and 10 are considered as
boundaries
so beyond these um
they could be uh invalid inputs so you
should consider them when you are
testing for your negative testing but
still they are not the valid values okay
so all other values within the range
that do not fall immediately between
um or around the boundaries are known as
the inner values in tosca or in test
case design sheets okay
so in our example of for quantity as you
can see
the 1 and 10 are our boundaries for that
particular instance
um the values between 2 and 9
are the inner values
and the values which are outside the
boundaries right so for example um
values like
11 12 13 right which are greater than 10
are also known as upper boundary values
and values which are lower than one say
for example zero or negative values
right so these will be lower boundary
values
so you can toggle uh your position of
your
instances based on
what kind of scenarios you want to
design for your test cases right so
based on that you have to define the
character and the position property for
your instance
okay so now let's see
how we can
create some instances for our attributes
which we created earlier and how we can
also toggle the character and position
properties for these instances in tosca
so now i am back in tosca where we
already created a test case design sheet
for our products page right and we had
defined different attributes
so now we need different instances
although i'm not going to fill in
instances for each and every attribute
in the session but i'm going to show you
at least one from each section right so
you can fill the others
um so in this administration part uh you
can create a in test designer you can
put the tester names
uh you can business contact you can put
the business analyst names as different
instances
and test cycle
let's see how we can create an instance
here right so when you right click
you can see there is an option called
create instance click on that
and now you will get
an option to create your own instance
under the instances okay
so
it's not possible to create sub
instances you can only create
instances for each attribute okay so for
test cycle i can say this is either
smoke
or i can create another instance here
called
regression right so there could be
different instances for the cycle
now coming to type of user
i can create
an
user called or instance called
registered
and i can create another one as new
right so there are two instances
similarly um
for uh products right so
for quantity uh we can create different
instances
like the quantity could be one it could
be two
it could be
three or as usual so you can put
instances different instances for
different product names
uh different prices right for those
products
um
similarly for checkout right so for
payment information
you can say credit card
okay
and
you can say then
uh internet banking
or you can say upi
okay so these are different payment
information types
similarly um in verification type of
attribute right so here you can create
an instance for message
so this could be either a success
message
or
it could be
a failure message right so two types of
instances
similarly uh you can create instances
for all your attributes right
so now um as you can see we have created
some instances right uh but still
you don't see any difference right so
the number of uh
instances for this sheet has not
increased right so you can still see at
as a one sheet
but
now um what you can do is we can also
add instances for this particular sheet
itself right so that we can have
different combinations of one particular
test case okay
so
i can create now different instances and
you will see there are different columns
which are being added here okay
so for um
my instances um i can just say
so
test case one
um i can say test case two
and test case three
right
so you can see um
now there are three different test cases
um and i have got different attributes
and different instances
for all these three different test cases
which could be three different business
flows right now
and
in real world uh you can also put them
as requirement ids or you can even put
it as your jira ids right or your test
case ids so that you can have hundreds
of test cases in this particular sheet
and all of these test cases will have
different combinations of test data
right so how you can do that
you can go um
to this particular test cycle right so
let me
just close this and you will see
the instances which we have created now
you can select values for different test
cases okay
now for example this test cycle has got
different instances now i can select
a value from these two different
instance so either i can
make it smoke
i can make this regression
right
so i can select type of user uh
registered or new
okay
similarly um i can select quantity
what
quantity this will be right
and i can select different payment
options here
so
one for each type of test case
i can say this is a success this is a
success this may be a failure because
this is not yet implemented
in my application okay so as you can see
now
there are there could be different test
cases and each test case could have a
different
business flow right
so as you can see you can cover
a lot of scenarios in just one test case
sheet by defining different attributes
and different instances of those
attributes right now you can divide your
test cases based on all the scenarios so
that you have got coverage all across
the application with different test data
okay
now um
we have talked about instances we
haven't talked about the properties
right so
on the menu but if you go to the test
case design sheet section right you will
see there are different options here
here you can also toggle the business
relevance okay
which we talked about earlier and you
can also toggle position and toggle
character so these are the two
properties which we discussed
now
if i go to each instance okay
so
by default um
this position is inner and the character
is valid so these are the two default
values which you can see in the
properties section
i can toggle
here so when you
press this toggle character it will
change the character type okay so it
will change it to invalid
and i can also toggle the position to
make it a boundary value
okay
and
i can also make it uh
if you do it three times then it will be
a straight through instance okay and you
will see the icon also changes when you
toggle this particular character right
similarly i can do it for type of user
okay
i can select the instance and i can
make it a straight through instance so
every instance should have
a straight through value right so that
um when you execute your test cases uh
your state through test case should pass
okay
um
and i can toggle the position to either
make it a boundary value right so
the quantity 1 could be a boundary value
10 could be a boundary value but 2 could
be
the inner
position values okay
similarly um
you can
create different instances and you can
put your character and position based on
your scenario
okay
so this is how um
you design your test case with different
instances
and
different instances can be considered as
different test cases in your test design
sheet
uh later we'll also talk about how you
can create different templates out of
your test cases and you can link your
test design sheet to a template
and then you will see the magic
how tosca can automatically create
different test cases out of this test
design sheet
so once you design this test sheet
completely
then your test case creation becomes a
lot easier
okay
so that i will see in some of the later
sessions
you